Guide to the Eric Hutchinson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Eric Hutchinson papers
1954-1982
SC0809
Hutchinson, Eric.
1 Linear feet
Although Hutchinson's professional field was chemistry, these papers pertain to his interest in history. They primarily relate to his research (done in the late 1960s) on scientific research in England prior to World War II and includes notes on the Department of Scientific and Industrial Research, the Chemistry Research Board, National Physical Laboratory, Physics Research Board, and the Radio Research Board and his typescript paper "The Radio Research Board and the Early History of Radio Direction Finding." Materials pertaining to Stanford University's history include Helen Dwight Fisher's paper on Leland Stanford, photocopy of the minutes from the first faculty meeting, 1891, correspondence with Joshua Lederberg on Medical School history, 1982, and a photograph of D. S. Jordan with Prof. Franklin, ca. 1926. Other items in the collection include miscellaneous correspondence with James Beck, Philip A. Leighton, and Edward Shils, 1969-77; and a genealogy booklet on the Hoadley family, 1972.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Eric Hutchinson, born in England in 1920, was educated at the University of Cambridge (1938-1945), earning all three of his degrees in chemistry. He taught at Sheffield University and Fordham University, before joining the Stanford faculty in 1949. In addition to his research and teaching duties, he served a term as academic secretary to the University; designed the shields and flags that represent the University, the Office of the President, the graduate division and the seven schools; and wrote a history of Stanford's department of chemistry. He became emeritus in 1983 and died on November 14, 2005.
Description of the Collection
Although Hutchinson's professional field was chemistry, these papers pertain to his interest in history. They primarily relate to his research (done in the late 1960s) on scientific research in England prior to World War II and includes notes on the Department of Scientific and Industrial Research, the Chemistry Research Board, National Physical Laboratory, Physics Research Board, and the Radio Research Board and his typescript paper "The Radio Research Board and the Early History of Radio Direction Finding." Materials pertaining to Stanford University's history include Helen Dwight Fisher's paper on Leland Stanford, photocopy of the minutes from the first faculty meeting, 1891, correspondence with Joshua Lederberg on Medical School history, 1982, and a photograph of D. S. Jordan with Prof. Franklin, ca. 1926. Other items in the collection include miscellaneous correspondence with James Beck, Philip A. Leighton, and Edward Shils, 1969-77; and a genealogy booklet on the Hoadley family, 1972.
Access Terms
Fisher, Helen Dwight.; Great Britain. Dept. of Scientific and Industrial Research.; Hutchinson, Eric.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Lederberg, Joshua; Leighton, Philip Albert, 1897-1983.; National Physical Laboratory (Great Britain).; Shils, Edward, 1910-1995.; Radar--Great Britain--History.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Beck, James, correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carnochan, "English Literary History at Stanford," reprint 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fisher, Helen Dwight, "Leland Stanford, 1824-1893," typescript carbon (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hoadley genealogy booklet, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hutchinson, "A Heraldic Shield for the Associates," Imprint, October 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4.1)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, letter, 1982, and photocopies of other letters and articles re SU Medical School history, 1954-78 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leighton, Philip A., letter, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photograph of D. S. Jordan with Prof. Franklin, ca. 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photograph and illustration showing SU banners designed by Hutchinson (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Radio Research Board and the Early History of Radio Direction Finding, typescript paper (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Shils, Edward, correspondence, 1969-72 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - S. U. faculty, minutes of first meeting (photocopy), Oct. 3, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lecture notes on scientific policy (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Research notes on air defense (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Research notes on RDF (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Research notes on DSIR [Department of Scientific and Industrial Research] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Research notes on Chemistry Research Board and DSIR (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Research notes on Chemistry Research Board and DSIR (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Research notes on Advisory Council and Chemistry Research Board (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Research notes on Radio Research Board (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Research notes on National Physical Laboratory (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Research notes on National Physical Laboratory and other topics (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Research notes on National Physical Laboratory and Physics Research Board (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Research notes on National Physical Laboratory and Physics Research Board (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Research notes Physics Research Board (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Research notes on DSIR (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Research notes on DSIR and other topics (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Research notes (metals, alloys, and DSIR) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Research notes, unlabelled (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Research notes, unlabelled (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Research notes, unlabelled (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Research notes, unlabelled (Box 2, Folder 12)